so it's a time and I think the New York
time I don't even know who cares where
it was published about and I you read it
so who cares my my referencing that I
watch the drop is you know episode that
refers to that article that did public
my phone said it's way too complex to
read on my thumb the climate change and
the current weather and our governments
are trying corporations are you been
kind of doing it to the best of their
ability but they suck at it I mean
governments can't they're just not
designed to create solutions they're
only in office for 44 years they're
currently owned by the 1% and work in
their own and their friends best
interest so which is not going to be the
rest now their best interest is also to
have a surviving planet so they're like
willing to maybe kinda sorta look into
kin to it and make some deals and spend
a lot of money making those deals but
they're not really designed to take
action whenever our governments take
action they then like simultaneously
they both don't have like don't kind of
give a what the populace thinks
they get in on a certain platform and
then don't follow through on that
platform aren't held accountable for
that and also they don't really care
because all they have to do is get it
elected again they just have to be the
best of the options that are available
and what they care about is the donor
money coming in to do that and so it's
just not they can't work in our in that
best interest its corporations and our
entire economic system is based on
passing the risk of environmental
catastrophes of health care of all of
this stuff it should be involved in the
cost of everything on to everyone and
who profits is the corporation who gets
to sell that thing and not have to
account for them and pay in any way for
what for the devastation and
issues that are causing sometimes
knowingly and a lot of times just
willfully ignorant like we don't even
want to know that we're causing problems
because having helped to possibly pay
for them you don't want to pay for it
that takes into our profit and all they
do if we created this entity that is by
law a sociopath I was gonna for all
those definitions confused but someone
who does not care at all with their
actions create or do and only care about
benefiting themselves and the
corporation's aren't going to do it and
governments aren't gonna do it and our
species is reliant on the fact that it
needs to get solved I don't have the
solution for climate change like I know
I'm not sitting on the and here it's how
we actually reverse it but understanding
the science of how we know that it's
human caused and what's causing it of
all of the were pumping into the
atmosphere and all of the in the actual
numbers if that's available to us
especially in a way that we can see it
it's not credible numbers like it's
actual visually represented in a way
that we can play with it and look at it
and not just okay it's a meme great but
how do I know it's true what's the
reference how do I go deeper into it and
see if I can believe that and what just
the bigger picture of science say about
it the more we have that and the more
when people have an idea on how to help
that I mean there are people cram videos
on how to like clean the ocean and how
to the truth is our world like our
bodies are extremely resilient and
amazing and healing themselves when we
stop doing to them um I'm body but
I don't know what I'm doing too so
it's hard to not do it anymore but
there's possibly something or it's just
all right how it goes at this planet
this planets forests and oceans and
systems are very resilient if we stop
but they also have points that they
can't come back from and they'll find a
new equilibrium possibly without human
life on them I would like that not to
happen I would like
us to survive this and not go extinct in
order for that to happen not just our
scientists have to come together we the
people have to come together and create
a way that we can understand what that
information is so that we can have
conversations around the dinner table
and around like if you're interested in
it you can easily find a group to have
those conversations with not this if
you're real someone on a chain like no
how can we what can we do to take action
and maybe just having the discussion of
what it means and what we would like to
know and is that information out there
whatever people feel called to but
having information available on
everything that especially climate
change in an organized and usable way
that people can trust and what is
something we can trust something that
we've just we've collectively decided is
trustworthy right like not this this
thing's trustworthy it's like no what
makes it trustworthy was is first person
I witness account incredible when it's
not recorded is a record incredible do
you have to have a geotag like do you
need to how much information do we need
to know that this happens the way the
person says it did at that time in place
and if it's not that is it just
discounted completely or is it just a
lower-ranking I would vote for lower
ranking that we have the best
information available and then figure it
out from there I obviously got
sidetracked by thinking about people
watching this it's like it flows better
when it's right here like that would be
on till 8:00
then I get to go do bedtime hey no
beanie so no and I'm live so you know
solve your own crowd see it's Emma
yeah like my brain he solves that
problem climate change is a very complex
problem we kind of sucked understanding
complex problems on a balls so it's
gonna take something new it's gonna take
collaboration and cooperative science to
discover doesn't mean everyone has to
come pretty complete looks like no you
can be a lab or a research team that's
just telling us what you found telling
us contributing to the conversation but
having conversations and having ways to
know ask questions and have them answer
to the best of the science out there as
well as having them like we can see
where they haven't been answered and can
me answer and what would that look like
and crowdsourcing science like everyone
gets to be a part of that where it makes
sense to be not not social media made
science like not in the same way of like
well I thought that no gravity doesn't
exist like that Democratic you know ray
democratic in how do we trust it that
isn't going to be different for every
different study right well we like it so
we're gonna trust it it's like no is it
what is the grading of the site it's
what was the and every different
discipline you come thorough and if they
want to
I'd like here's what makes a good
peer-reviewed biological study and I
can't think of the different types of
studies up in a biology here's what
makes a good drug trial and then we
grade them against each other how
confident are we that this drug is
life-saving versus just the new product
the company wants to put out there which
is exactly what it probably is like is
it actually better than what's out there
before is there less side effects or is
it just a different here like is it
actually better and can we make decision
based on on that stuff and it's all it's
all the other hand joined from climate
change to drugs here but personally i
would like to have information on drugs
and health but globally and for our
species we need to have information like
I get it it's out there if you want to
go and look at it it's it it exists is
Wikipedia pages on it but like we need
to come together and own something and
that we can trust to share knowledge and
collaborate and so that involves
compiling enough right not necessarily
trusting Wikipedia creating our own
version of the record Wikipedia of
databases and the infographics that that
come out of that to make it visual on
every different topic and people get to
keep out in their area of choosing and
contribute to it or you have you know
historians telling stories making
history come to life for everyone
scientists deciding on algorithms they
that grade science and ways to
communicate science to everyone that is
both meaningful to the person making the
science and the person discovering it
like reading about it and then we take
leaps forward with your cancer like that
we saw climate change like that because
when we're doing stuff and the open we
progress much much faster it doesn't
take it might still take ten years to a
study some teams studies take ten years
to do but during that process meet
reporting back with the information is
if that doesn't hurt the science some
studies that will hurt it another ones
it won't and when the all serious
butthurt at I don't know nothing of
wonder it would be really hurt to get
the information have the people in this
study any information about the study
but the point is you don't have this leg
between something being discovered it
being written up and published it can be
a really long process and then people
reading it and implementing it in order
to base the next discovery on it and
it's all happening simultaneously and
I'm just like we make that more rad or
there is the brainstorming and you don't
necessarily or make sense to repeat
experiments or repeating experiments
where it doesn't
it's not about necessarily you go and
being the first to discover it it's like
yeah I want to know about this and I
want to know about it maybe there's
three different teams working on the
same thing running the same experiment
independently and maybe you're helping
each other troubleshoot but it's like
you're collaborating on science right
hey like no we want kids because it's
not about who gets published first and
if it is about that we can figure that
out we can say these people co-created
this right they're all first authors and
here's all the second authors or
whatever it happens to be if you need to
have ego involved you'd allow you go to
be involved but you can still say like
no this is something like the equivalent
of having your name on a paper you can
still have just not be where you go part
of it you're like I got here first a
week before this person published it's
like yeah you can magically the other
person they put in just as much time
they were a week shy of doing it you're
just as likely to be that person like
why not say hey this team collaborated
and if you want to break it down as hey
this is my ID this was my idea
fine cool but what's gonna happen is
it's like you're involved and you can
see how involved people are based on how
everyone says right like who did 60% of
the work who did this who did this you
can see who does more of the work on
certain projects and accordingly like if
someone's involved in in dozens and
dozens of projects but barely that's
that's important like maybe you don't
even need to know so saying five minutes
on a project and they can it improve
versus spending of you know like
hundreds of hours almost different it's
okay why time we should be like global
warming you like bedtime not really okay